<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[de-escalation.training]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[de-escalation.training]]></description>
        <link>http://de-escalation.club/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 22:35:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://de-escalation.club/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Brilliant course. It has given me the confidence to remain calm when my son is very upset – keeping calm is the best thing for him.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://de-escalation.club/f9170c2a-13da-4a01-bb41-6f96a4555bc8/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f9170c2a-13da-4a01-bb41-6f96a4555bc8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 22:35:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Many of the team at Skybound have spent the last 3 days on a positive handling course. We have previously been trained by Team Teach. However this time we decided to try a different company and used D.ESCAL8. The course was fantastic! The presenter Des, was amazing. We prefer to never use restraints with any of our clients, however there are times when we may need to be able to release ourselves from hair pulls, pinches, bites etc. which is the reason we do positive handling training. The course was excellent, it emphasised not using restraints and stayed focused on always building a good relationship with the individual. It taught us essential safety skills, but always kept the individual with a disability and their quality of life as the focus. There was no work on overpowering the individual, there was no need to with the techniques we were shown. The techniques focused on using movement and positive interactions to de-escalate serious situations. We have been discussing possibly putting on a course to train parents and also a course for self employed ABA therapists/consultants. If this would be of interest to you, please let us know.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.facebook.com/skyboundautismtherapies/posts/1012357205522046</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b01afeff-e217-40b4-8d19-69e875dc4cf6</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 18:29:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[— V.W. - Service Manager]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I have been working in care for 12 years. In that time I have been trained with a number of companies delivering training on de-escalation techniques and physical restraint procedures. Since moving more formally into the disability sector and becoming a service manager I have been struck by how inappropriate these methods are to children with a learning disability and autism. They neither take into account the additional difficulties these children face or the impact these difficulties can have on behaviour. They also do not consider the stress that restraint puts on that child leading to possible further escalation.As a manager I now get to decide what training to have and when D.ESCAL8 was suggested to me I admit to thinking “what’s new?” I felt that this was another programme designed for ‘naughty children’. When I spoke to Des I understood the ethos but it sounded a bit ‘pie in the sky’. When I finally commissioned some bespoke training in September 2015 I ate my words. I was impressed with the content, the presentation, the personalisation of information and the unique ability of the trainer to humanise the work we do. I immediately commissioned another full course to train my entire staff team to ensure that we all signed up to this way of working. To understand where behaviour comes from and how to respond appropriately and sensitively. I enjoyed the confidence that came from this and the realisation that sometimes to walk away, ‘give in’ and ‘not win’ were all considered ‘best practice’. This changed the mind-set of the staff team. They suddenly felt empowered and re-connected with the way they feel they should be looking after disabled children. More than a month after training the staff are still buzzing. They have used this and I am heartened to hear them talking about behaviour and planning for behaviour in the way the training has taught them. Ofsted also visited us the day after we completed the training and were impressed with our decision to step outside the mould for Plymouth and commission such an innovative training course for what is and will always be a very sensitive and delicate area of care for such a vulnerable group of children. I am delighted to say that this training has transformed a tired and anxious team into a positive and confident one.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://de-escalation.club/i-have-been-working-in-care-for-12-years-in-that-time-i-hav/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a8ed7bdc-a56a-42a6-95f4-82ed763a239b</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 18:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[— B.M. Senior Home Manager]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Firstly apologies for my late feedback, I wanted time to reflect and digest what we learnt and how it compared to previous training i have had.  So: My previous experience of this type of training is built upon Skip and more recently PBM, in both cases I have managed packages of support that provide support to people who often found themselves in distressing situations and in all of my previous training we reverted to crisis management. When I first experienced PBM I described it as advanced compared to Skip, but essentially the results were the same - staff decide when somebody is in crisis and when to redirect them. I think the day to day work involved with PBM is spot on, establish primary and secondary responses to known behaviours and triggers does tend to keep people from distressing situations. It is the crisis management laden with defensive stances, that feels like a change. I never questioned it until d.escal8 and then it hit me like a sudden awakening. To treat a crisis in the same way as your prevention strategies makes this training truly holistic and now I have registered it it is the only way I can see physical interventions passing the ‘mum test’ - I would want my relatives treated with this level of respect. In terms of the training I felt that Des was outstanding, he worked hard to bring the whole group off our emotional baseline and then taught us how to cope and react without affecting anybodies dignity. Initially I felt the group were hesitant and didn’t necessarily get it (myself included) but by the end of day 3 we were all engaged and mopping it up. In a previous role I was given some really great coaching by PBM tutors that were very thorough in ensuring we practised techniques over and over. However it wasn’t until my first real incident that I used any of the techniques and rather predictably my training went out the window and I reacted in my own distress. I learnt from that and adapted my approach, but with all of the teams I worked with going through similar experiences I know that scores of people would have used unlicensed techniques and justified it in the name of experience. By taking us off baseline Des gave us the opportunity to have that first experience in a safe environment and i felt that the whole group went away much more emotionally self aware. Many thanks for an enlightening 3 day workout.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://de-escalation.club/bm-senior-home-manager/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e4e8a777-ae04-4d16-b2e1-5eb17bad20b0</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 18:09:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>It is not the only thing training is about http://d8.is/b4 https://twitter.com/desc/status/665673630488125440 ...</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/DeESCAL8/status/665674902389813248</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2d472ae9-d6a8-4e71-b3f3-834b1b1644eb</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 23:27:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We have had a lot of enquiries about the positive handling course our team participated in a month ago. Many... http://fb.me/7SHFJ1PNr</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/SkyboundTherapy/status/717989513092530177</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7203c925-7154-471b-b20c-d3cca41a5105</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 23:27:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>"Those who are easily shocked should be shocked more often." - Mae West</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/descooke/status/667143695486029824</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">31e1d159-43f5-4704-941d-003e5477ac27</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 23:27:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[De-escalating with D.ESCAL8]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>De-escalating with D.ESCAL8</h1><p>It has been a long break. And times have been interesting. The big update is that Archie has now finally returned to respite, and seems delighted to be back (it was very much his choice). The path back was not entirely smooth. For a while Archie's behaviour was quite simply dangerous.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/fab4da12bdccaa6ed6d5479368383bb266938663.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://alifeunlimited.wordpress.com/2015/05/25/de-escalating-with-d-escal8/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6c80fe98-f18f-400d-9306-c1a0f45b09fe</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 22:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I'd highly recommend this @DeESCAL8 course #PBS #PositiveHandling #MovementNOTRestraint https://twitter.com/skyboundtherapy/status/717989513092530177 ...</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/rhianthorne1408/status/721037937887092736</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c94a858c-57dd-473b-8db0-be6cea06b2ac</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>